Gonzalo Reyes

A software engineer enthusiast who enjoys solving real-world problems related to community building, finance and education. Currently, working toward the improvement of the learning experience of students at SUNY Plattsburgh through convenient and sophisticated software applications

EDUCATION

State University of New York at Plattsburgh

PLATTSBURGH, NY — AUGUST 2016 - PRESENT (EXPECTED MAY 2020)

- Computer Science B.S | GPA: 3.89
- Honors: Academic Achievement in Computer Science (Spring '18)

EXPERIENCE

Codecademy / Software Engineer Intern

NEW YORK, NY — JUNE 2019 - AUGUST 2019

- Co-engineered the new *Code Challenges* feature, an assessment type that allows learners to type and execute code to reinforce their knowledge
- Demoed the Code Challenges MVP to the company stakeholders in the monthly all-hands meeting
- Took initiative and stepped forward to contribute to the migration of React components and Javascript files to Typescript
- Collaborated with designers and engineers to launch a new <u>interactive 404</u>
 page that renders a custom endless runner game built with PhaserJS
- Worked on frontend improvements including redesigning the footer and catalog, converting legacy .erb pages to react and fixing accessibility bugs
- Reviewed and tested production-ready code. Utilized Jest and Enzyme for unit and component testing, TestCafe for E2E testing and RSpec for rails

Coding Hub / Co-founder, President, and Lead Engineer

PLATTSBURGH, NY - SEPTEMBER 2018 - PRESENT

- Spearhead an agile team of 20 members to plan, build, test and deploy 4 software apps to assist students and organizations on campus
- Establish coding standards and write detailed documentation to make applications maintainable and allow new members to quickly understand and collaborate on the projects
- Successfully explain highly-technical concepts to university staff to gain approval and receive support to deploy our applications
- Conduct bi-weekly stand-up meetings and encourage team collaboration through code reviews, pair programming, and weekly lightning talks
- Introduce and set up CI/CD pipeline with CircleCI in our workflow to improve development speed and ensure code quality
- Introduce and use Slack and Asana for team and project management

Interbank / Data Analyst Intern

LIMA, PE - JUNE 2018 - AUGUST 2018

- Developed a supervised ML classifier with python to categorize customer reviews with an accuracy of 92% as measured by a confusion matrix
- Built 15 fully responsive banners for the mobile app and website using HTML5, CSS3, and vanilla JS to do A/B testing and test experiments
- Proactively participated in weekly committee meetings of 5 people to show and analyze tests results as well as propose and discuss new experiments

reyesegonzalo@gmail.com

www.iamgonchi.com

https://github.com/gonzen2310

www.linkedin.com/in/gonzalo-reyes

(518) 466 - 1229

LANGUAGES

Java, JavaScript, Python, Ruby, Kotlin, C++, TypeScript, Dart, SQL, HTML5, CSS3

SKILLS

Web development, Android, UI/UX, Github, Project Manager, Algorithms, Teaching

TOP PROJECTS

Shuttler / Lead Android Engineer

App that locates the college shuttles in real-time

- Designed prototype using AdobeXD
- Built Android app with Kotlin and Java
- Used Firebase Auth to authenticate users, Cloud Firestore to manage real-time data, and Cloud Functions to send notifications
- Integrated Google Maps API to display shuttle location and monitor geofences
- Utilized Android Jetpack components and tools to develop a robust MVVM application
- Rendered Adobe AE animations with Lottie

Tutoring Hub / PM & Lead Engineer

Website to rate academic tutors on Campus

- Designed and developed Single Page
 Application with React + Typescript
- Integrated Redux for UI state management
- Built a RESTful API with Express.js and MongoDB that serves data to the front-end
- Integrated Cloudinary SDK to host and manage static media assets
- Wrote a python script to populate DB by parsing a CSV file with a list of active tutors
- Utilized Jest for unit testing and Enzyme for React component testing

OneSpot / Full-stack Developer

Web app that helps you track job applications

- Architected a monolith Rails GraphQL API that communicates with a React front-end
- Leveraged React ecosystem by using Hooks and Context API to manage states
- Integrated Apollo client to query back-end
- Utilized React beautiful DnD for smooth drag and drop interactions
- Designed an ER diagram with Lucidchart and created a database with Postgresql